<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>english on swissbib data blog</title><link>https://swissbib.github.io/tags/english/</link><description>Recent content in english on swissbib data blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>de-ch</language><managingEditor>swissbib-ub@unibas.ch (project swissbib)</managingEditor><webMaster>swissbib-ub@unibas.ch (project swissbib)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 16:07:50 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://swissbib.github.io/tags/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Humans Learn about the Data from a Support Vector Machine</title><link>https://swissbib.github.io/blog/machine_learning/support_vector_machine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 16:07:50 +0200</pubDate><author>swissbib-ub@unibas.ch (project swissbib)</author><guid>https://swissbib.github.io/blog/machine_learning/support_vector_machine/</guid><description>Machine Learning may look mystical, although it is based on the mathematical discipline of statistics. If the learning process is done with a fixed data set, Machine Learning can be structured into two distinct groups of tasks, supervised and unsupervised learning. In supervised learning, the artificial machine is trained with a set of training data with a target value, each. In the first blog article, the feature records and their associated target value have been introduced for the swissbib project at hand.</description></item><item><title>A Machine Learning Approach with Ensemble Methods</title><link>https://swissbib.github.io/blog/machine_learning/ensemblemethods/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 13:48:19 +0200</pubDate><author>swissbib-ub@unibas.ch (project swissbib)</author><guid>https://swissbib.github.io/blog/machine_learning/ensemblemethods/</guid><description>The notion of Machine Learning includes a wide group of statistical algorithms where a computer system learns on a set of training data and, after having completed its learning phase, uses its experience to generate predictions on new, unknown data. In the context of the capstone project of an advanced online training course at EPF Lausanne, a swissbib admirer takes the challenge to do Machine Learning with a set of library catalogue data in MARC 21 format.</description></item><item><title>Why machine learning in the swissbib project</title><link>https://swissbib.github.io/blog/machine_learning/background_en/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 15:50:09 +0200</pubDate><author>swissbib-ub@unibas.ch (project swissbib)</author><guid>https://swissbib.github.io/blog/machine_learning/background_en/</guid><description>For what feels like two or three years now, it has been almost impossible to find articles on the subject of data and information in which terms such as &amp;ldquo;Machine Learning&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Artificial Intelligence&amp;rdquo; (AI) or &amp;ldquo;Neural Networks&amp;rdquo; are not mentioned at least once and described as the recipe for success for the future. Should this mean that what we have been doing over the last 12 years is outdated and no longer relevant?</description></item></channel></rss>